A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Office Files of Richard M. Krasno FA563
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Office Files of Richard M. Krasno
1978-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Krasno, Richard M.
Ford Foundation
FA563
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Alphabetical
Scope and Contents
Files include documentation of selection of projects, meetings, reviews, and workshops.
Biographical / Historical
Richard M. Krasno's career in education has included positions in academia, philanthropy, and government. Krasno worked for several years at the Ford Foundation. In 1974, he joined the Foundation as a Program Advisor in the Latin America and the Caribbean, Brazil Program. He then became a Program Officer in the umbrella Latin America and the Caribbean Program before moving to the Middle East and Africa Program.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Krasno served in the United States Department of Education as Deputy Assistant to the Secretary of Education. He then had executive positions at the Institute of International Education, the Monterey Institute of International Studies, and the William R. Kenan, Jr, Charitable Trust. He later became Lead Director for Ladenburg Thalmann Financial Services.
Krasno earned a Ph.D. from Stanford University and worked as an assistant professor at the University of Chicago prior to joining the Ford Foundation.
- Bangladesh, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
- Indonesia Textbook Project, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- IDRC -- Research Review Advisory Group (RRAG), 1978 (Box 1)
- International Education -- Business -- Sutton -- Pending, 1979 (Box 1)
- International Studies Review, 1979 (Box 1)
- Liberia Trip, 1978 April 5-9 (Box 1)
- Mexico Trip File, 1978 June (Box 1)
- National Awards Systems Review, 1978 (Box 1)
- Nutrition and Food Policy, 1979 (Box 1)
- Regional Education DAP Supplement, 1978 (Box 1)
- Staff Memoranda, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- Trustees Meetings, 1979 (Box 1)
- UNICEF, 1980 (Box 1)
- USAID -- FWAERTP, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
- West Africa, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
- Women, 1980 (Box 1)
- Women's Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
- Workshop on Higher Education on West Bank, 1979 (Box 1)
- Zimbabwe, 1980 (Box 1)